[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&GT；&GT；Kyle：好吧，让我们跳进去吧。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: All right, so let's jump in.
让我们谈谈并行与异步。
Let's talk about parallel versus async.
打个比方，如果我们试图理解什么是平行与异步，
Metaphorically, if we try to understand what parallel is versus async,
大多数人把它们混为一谈，认为它们基本上是一回事
most people conflate those and think that they're basically the same thing or
JavaScripts版本的Parallel被称为Async或其他什么。
JavaScripts version of parallel is called async or whatever.
事实并非如此。
It's not really the case.
只有在最高的地方，如果你真的从50，000英尺的高度眯着眼睛的话。
Only at the highest level if you really squinted from 50,000 feet up.
你会不会考虑并行性和异步性
Might you look at parallelism and asynchronicity and
说他们是一回事。
say they're the same thing.
有重要的区别。
There's important differences.
所以，让我给你一个比喻，如何解决这个问题。
So let me give you metaphorically how to kind of work through that.
并行性与非并行性，我们将分组异步
Parallelism versus non-parallelism, which we'll sort of group asynchronicity
现在变成非并行性，我会更多地解释这一点。
into non-parallelism for now and I'll explain that more.
所以非并行性就像你在
So non-parallelism would be like you waiting in line at
过山车游乐园。
amusement park for a roller coaster.
排队的人很多，你终于排到了队伍的前面。
Lots of people in line and you finally get up to the front of the line.
那里有一个有30个座位的过山车，但他们只让你上车。
There's a roller coaster there with 30 seats on it but they only let you on.
而且你是唯一一个可以在任何特定地点骑马的人。
And you're the only person that can ride at any given point.
所以即使有30个人乘坐的能力，在任何给定的时刻，
So even though there's capacity for 30 people to ride, at any given moment,
只有一个人在骑车。
only one person is riding the ride.
这将是不平行的。
That would be non-parallel.
我们稍后会给出这些不同的术语。
We'll give those different terms in a moment.
它们将是不平行的，而如果你排队的话。
They'd be non-parallel versus if you waited in line.
你到了那里，然后30个人上了过山车。
You got up there and then 30 people loaded onto the roller coaster.
当过山车运行时，
And when the roller coaster is running,
你们所有30个人都在完全相同的时刻经历着过山车。
all 30 of you are experiencing the roller coaster at exactly the same instant.
这是更多的并行性。
That's more parallelism.
所以在计算的意义上，并行性是通过线程来表达的。
So in a computing sense, parallelism is expressed through threads.
最常见的表达方式是线程。
Most commonly expressed through threads.
我可以在我的系统中的一个CPU核心上有一个线程的想法。
The idea that I could have one thread on one CPU core in my system.
还有另一条线。
And another thread.
它们有点像需要发生的操作的队列，或者操作和
They're are kind of like queues of actions that need to happen, or operations and
必须发生。
need to happen.
在任何给定的时刻，一个核心都可以执行这些操作中的一个，并且
At any given instant, one core could be doing one of those operations, and
就在同一时刻，
in exactly that same moment,
另一个操作可能正在不同的核心上进行。
another operation could be happening on a different core.
那是真的。
That's true.
诚实与善良的并行性。
Honest to goodness parallelism.
现在，即使有你可能拥有的最强大的机器。
Now, even with the most powerful of the machines that you may have out there.
你可能有一个16核，或者你有一个32核。
You may have a 16 core, or maybe you have a 32.
我们中的大多数人可能在我们的计算机中有4，8个内核。
Most of us probably have 4, 8 cores in our computers.
32个线程远远不足以运行具有以下类型的现代操作系统
32 threads is not nearly enough to run a modern operating system with the types of
事情，我们在运行我们运行的所有程序时所做的多任务处理。
thing, the multitasking that we do with running all the programs we run.
即使是您的浏览器，您的单个浏览器也可能仅占用10或15个线程
Even your browser, your single browser might take up 10 or 15 threads just for
它在网页上执行的基本操作。
basic operations that it does on a web page.
所以如果你曾经打开过Chrome的任务管理器
So if you've ever opened up the Task Manager of Chrome and
看到所有正在运行的进程，它会并行运行大量内容。
seen all the processes that are running, it runs an awful lot of stuff In parallel.
所以因为我们没有无限数量的内核，操作系统实际上
So because we don't have infinite numbers of cores, the operating system actually
有一个我们称之为虚拟线程的层。
has a layer that we would call sort of virtual threads.
并且它负责调度虚拟线程。
And it takes care of scheduling the virtual threads.
它可以分发数万个这样的东西。
It can hand out tens of thousands of those.
并且它负责尝试跨核心安排这些任务，因此
And it takes care of trying to schedule those across the cores so
他们在尽可能多的同时发生。
that they're happening as and as much in parallel as possible.
从您的编程角度来看，您并不真正关心这一点，或者
From the perspective of your programming, you don't really care about that or
甚至知道他们在什么内核上运行。
even know what cores they're running on.
您只需假设这两件事在不同的线程上，操作
You just assume that these two things are on separate threads, that the operating
系统将做正确的事情，并确保它们分别运行。
system will do the right thing and make sure that they're running separately.
对，所以显然并行性是关于优化的，对吧？
Right, so obviously parallelism is about optimization, right?
如果我有一大堆事情要做。
If I've got a bunch of things to do.
我不想等到第一组任务
I don't wanna wait to do the second set of tasks until the first set of tasks is
完成了，如果可以同时做这两件事，如果我能更快完成，
finished, if it's possible to do both at the same time, if I can get done faster,
好多了。
that's much better.
并行性是关于优化的。
Parallelism is about optimization.
好的，这就解释了并行性。
All right, so that explains parallelism.
那么异步性呢？
What about asynchronicity?
嗯，异步性，我们生活的世界，
Well, asynchronicity, the world that we live in,
在异步性中，将我们移动到单个线程。
in asynchronicity, moves us to a single thread.
JavaScript内部的编程甚至完全在单个线程上运行
The programming inside of our JavaScript runs entirely on a single thread even
尽管浏览器可以访问多个线程甚至JavaScript
though the browser may have access to multiple threads and even the JavaScript
例如，引擎节点可以在后台使用数百个线程。
engine node for example could use hundreds of threads in the background.
但我们的程序只在单个线程中运行。
But our program only runs in a single thread.
在任何给定的时刻，只有一行JavaScript在运行
At any given instant there is only one line of JavaScript running
在JavaScript引擎中。
in the JavaScript engine.
理论上，您可以使用JavaScript引擎的多个实例
You could in theory spend multiple instances of the JavaScript engine
在完全独立的线程上，是的，看起来就像
on entirely separate threads and yes that would be that would look like
多线程编程，但它们无法以任何有用的方式进行通信。
multithreaded programming but they couldn't communicate in any useful way.
网络工作者就是试图弥合这一差距的一个例子。
Web workers is an example of trying to bridge that gap.
Web worker是一种将完全独立的线程旋转起来的方法，但是
Web workers is a way of spinning up an entirely separate thread but
这不是JavaScript的事情，这是浏览器的事情。
that's not a JavaScript thing, that's a browser thing.
Web平台定义了Web工作者的概念。
The web platform defines the notion of web workers.
在整个单独的线程中旋转，
Spins up in a whole separate thread,
JavaScript引擎的一个完整的单独实例。
a whole separate instance of the JavaScript engine.
就JavaScript而言，这两件事彼此并不了解
As JavaScript is concerned, those two things don't know about each other
他们没有任何重叠，他们没有共享变量，什么都没有。
they don't have any overlap, they're not sharing variables, there's nothing.
好消息是，我们不必担心任何胡说八道
The good news is, we don't have to worry about any of the nonsense that
线程编程的位置。
threaded programming as to where.
我们不需要处理新的税收和信号灯
We don't have to deal with new taxes and semaphores and
所有的疯狂和共享资源锁定。
all of the craziness and shared resource locking.
我们知道在给定的时间内只能运行一个函数。
We know that only one function can be running in a given time.
如果有两个单独的JavaScript引擎在运行，这并不重要，因为
And if you have two separate JavaScript engines running, it doesn't matter because
反正他们也不会在同一个共享空间里工作。
they're not gonna be operating over the same shared space anyway.
现在，幸运的是，网络工作者确实为我们提供了一条沟通路径
Now, web workers fortunately do give us a communication path
通过异步事件。
through asynchronous events.
因此，即使它们在功能上是在独立的线程上操作。
So even though they are functionally operating on independent threads.
他们不能以线程的方式进行通信，他们必须重新进行通信
They cannot communicate in a threaded fashion, they have to communicate back on
通过事件循环的单线程概念。
that single threaded notion through the event loop.